I like to focus on what you
J'aime me concentrer sur ce que vous
do before you go into a stressful presentation.
faites avant d'aller dans une présentation stressante.
Of course,
Bien sûr,
inevitably people are going to ask,
inévitablement, les gens vont demander,
what do you do during the presentation?
que faites-vous pendant la présentation ?
If you have that moment where your heart starts
Si vous avez ce moment où votre cœur commence
racing,
course,
your mouth is going dry,
votre bouche devient sèche,
your face is getting red,
votre visage devient rouge,
you know,
vous savez,
probably from your own experience how quickly that goes into
probablement à partir de votre propre expérience à quelle vitesse cela va dans
a kind of death spiral,
une sorte de spirale de la mort,
so i want to tell you that you actually have the control
donc je veux vous dire que vous avez réellement le contrôle
to pull yourself out of that,
pour vous sortir de cela,
and what you need to do is pause
et ce que vous devez faire est pause
and collect your thoughts.
et recueillir vos pensées.
That's ok?
C'est ok ?
It does not come across as painfully
It does not come across as painfully
awkward to other people,
awkward to other people,
they actually see it as a sign of confidence.
they actually see it as a sign of confidence.
The second one slow
The second one slow
your breathing,
your breathing,
make sure it's deep trigger that relax
make sure it's deep trigger that relax
ation response.
ation response.
This is about your nervous system,
This is about your nervous system,
speaking to your brain and telling you that you're in a safe
speaking to your brain and telling you that you're in a safe
situation. Another thing that people do when they get nervous speaking as
situation. Another thing that people do when they get nervous speaking as
they start to collapse,
they start collapse,
they start to touch their arms and touch
ils commencent à toucher leurs bras et à toucher
their faces in their necks,
leurs visages dans leur cou,
and they don't move around and they get what we call
et ils ne se déplacent pas et ils obtiennent ce que nous appelons
penguin arms,
les bras de pingouin,
where they pin their upper arms to their bodies
où ils épinglent leurs bras supérieurs à leur corps
are afraid they don't know what to do with their arms,
ont peur qu'ils ne savent pas quoi faire avec leurs bras,
stop yourself from doing that here's,
vous arrêter de le faire ici's,
how you can do it.
comment vous pouvez le faire.
Hold something,
Tenez quelque chose,
have a slide advancer,
avoir un aventurier de diapositive,
hold it away from your body carry of water bottle
tenir loin de votre corps porté de bouteille d'eau ou
or if you're standing at a podium,
vous êtes debout sur un podium,
put your arms on the podium,
mettez vos bras sur le podium,
do things that force you to hold
faites des choses qui vous forcent à tenir
your arms and your hands away from your body
vos bras et vos mains loin de votre corps
that will help you to feel more confident
qui vous aidera à vous sentir plus confiant
and powerful,
et puissant,
and it will also signal to other people that you feel powerful
et il signalera également à d'autres personnes que vous vous sentez puissant
and confident the key is.
et confiant la clé est.
Don't let the primitive fighter flight part of your brain
Ne laissez pas le combattant primitif voler partie de votre cerveau
take over.
prendre le contrôle.
You are not going to be very good at telling yourself to calm
Vous ne serez pas très bon à vous dire de se calmer
down,
vers le bas,
and we're very,
et nous sommes très,
very bad doing that.
très mauvais à faire cela.
But your body can calm you down,
Mais votre corps peut vous calmer,
so if you say calm down to yourself when you're
donc si vous dites calme à vous-même lorsque vous êtes
anxious,
Anxious,
you go,
you go,
oh my gosh,
oh my gosh,
i'm really,
i 'm really,
really anxious.
really anxious.
So you get a kind of rebound,
So you get a kind of rebound,
the anxiety.
the anxiety.
If you change your body language.
If you change your body language.
Jj,
Jj,
you're walking yourself down away from that
you're walking yourself down away from that
ledge,
ledge,
and that really comes and your nervous system
and that really comes and your nervous system
and allows you to regain your composure.
and allows you to regain your composure.